mipi.org 2019-11-30

# 

At MIPI Alliance, we respect your privacy. We want to ensure that you get the information, content, and experiences that matter most to you. MIPI Alliance is committed to protecting the privacy of its members, customers, volunteers, and other contacts. It is the policy of MIPI Alliance to not request, collect, or maintain personal data other than what is required for the administration of the Alliance.

#### Scope

This privacy policy applies to all personal data processed by full-time and part-time employees, members and volunteers when acting on behalf of MIPI Alliance, contractors and partners doing business on behalf of MIPI Alliance, as well as all business processes conducted by MIPI Alliance.

#### What information do we collect?

MIPI Alliance collects the following personal data in line with the use purposes explained in a subsequent section:

  * Your name and contact details
  * Online profile data/usage
  * IP address
  * Social media profile information (optional)
  * Purchasing and payment information in relation to the processing of membership, event registration, or other requested services
  * Registration and participation in MIPI Alliance events and activities
  * Subscription preferences
  * Information about the device(s) you use
  * Information about service usage
  * Cookies
  * Authentication data
  * Location information
  * Other information you upload or provide to us

#### How do we use your information?

MIPI Alliance uses (and, where specified, shares) your personal information for the following purposes:

  * **To process transactions**  
MIPI Alliance uses personal information such as name, physical address, telephone number, email address, and company/institution to engage in interactions with you, including contacting you about your membership, event participation, or other organization activities. We use financial/credit card and payment information to process your order and may need to share some of this information with delivery services, credit card clearinghouses, and other third parties to complete the transaction.To provide support or other services. MIPI Alliance may use your personal information to provide you with support or other services that you have requested. For instance, MIPI Alliance may use your personal information to provide requested whitepapers or specifications, or to respond directly to your requests for information, including registrations for events or webinars, or other specific requests. MIPI Alliance may also pass your contact information to the appropriate MIPI Alliance participants, contractors, or processors for further follow-up related to your interests.  
 
  * **To provide information and updates about MIPI Alliance program offerings, events, and organization activities**  
MIPI Alliance may use your personal information to provide you with notices of new program offerings, membership news and service developments.  
 
  * **To select content, improve quality, and facilitate** **use** **of the websites**  
MIPI Alliance may use your personal information, including the information gathered as a result of site navigation and electronic protocols and cookies (including third-party cookies), to help create and personalize website content, improve website quality, track marketing campaign responsiveness, evaluate page response rates, conduct usability testing, and facilitate your use of the websites (for example, to facilitate navigation and the login process, avoid duplicate data entry, enhance security, keep track of shopping cart additions, and preserve order information between sessions).  
 
  * **To communicate with you about a meeting, conference, or event**  
We may communicate with you about a meeting, conference, or event hosted or co-sponsored by MIPI Alliance. This may include information about the event’s content, event logistics, payment, updates, and additional information related to the event. Information you provide when registering for or participating in a conference managed or co-sponsored by parties, other than or in addition to MIPI Alliance may be shared with those parties, and the treatment of such information is further subject to the privacy policies of those parties. MIPI Alliance and any conference co-sponsors may contact you after the event about the event, subsequent iterations of the event and related events. Please note that MIPI Alliance conference, meeting or event organizers, co-sponsors, exhibitors, and other third parties may directly request your personal information at their conference booths or presentations. Providing your information to them is optional, and you should review their privacy policies to address your particular needs and concerns about how they will treat your personal information.  
 
  * **To provide access to member websites or portals**  
If you are a member of MIPI Alliance, we may, with your permission, use your personal information to provide you access to member-restricted user portals, websites, or work group areas. We may, with your permission, include your information in work group directories. We may also enable private member-to-member messaging. Member privacy and communication settings can be managed by users within the member website (Causeway). Any additional questions related to access to, removal from, or custom communication settings can be sent to [admin@team.mipi.org](mailto:admin@team.mipi.org).  
 
  * **To document and administer participation in MIPI Alliance activities**  
If you are a member of MIPI Alliance, we may use your personal information to facilitate Alliance program participation and membership. MIPI Alliance participation is documented through various methods, e.g., rosters, submission documents, email reflectors, records of meeting attendance, responses to ballots, and participation lists.  
 
  * **To assist in your participation in MIPI Alliance activities**  
MIPI Alliance will communicate with you if you are participating in certain MIPI Alliance activities such as MIPI Alliance conferences, authoring or reviewing a document, or other activities. MIPI Alliance may send you information such as newsletters related to those activities.  
 
  * **To update you on relevant MIPI Alliance benefits, programs, and opportunities**  
MIPI Alliance may communicate with you regarding relevant MIPI Alliance benefits, programs, and opportunities available to you, through your membership with MIPI Alliance.  
 
  * **To engage with third parties**  
MIPI Alliance may share your personal data with third parties in connection with services that these individuals or entities are authorized to perform for or with MIPI Alliance. These third parties are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for MIPI Alliance or for the collaboration in which they and MIPI Alliance are contractually engaged (for example, conducting MIPI Alliance’s member satisfaction survey, or sending you information that you requested). These third parties are carefully selected by MIPI Alliance and obligated to keep your data secure.  
 
  * **To protect** **MIPI** **Alliance content and services**  
We may use your information to prevent potentially illegal activities and to enforce our terms and conditions. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address anomalous activity and to screen content to prevent abuse, such as spam. These efforts may, on occasion, result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions for some users.  
 
  * **To get feedback or input from you**  
In order to deliver products and services of most interest to our customers, from time to time, we may ask members, customers, volunteers, and website visitors to provide us input and feedback (for example through surveys, usability studies, focus groups).  
 
  * **To protect MIPI Alliance information assets as well as your own personal data**  
MIPI Alliance protects the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of MIPI Alliance information assets by following a risk management approach based on policies, standards, guidelines, and procedures to meet security objectives while supporting business and operational goals.

#### How can you control your information?

You can control the information we have about you and how we use it in several ways. If you are a registered user of the [member website (Causeway)](https://members.mipi.org/), you can review, revise, and correct the personal data that you have provided via your account in that system.

#### Opt Out

If you wish to opt-out of emails from MIPI Alliance, those who have a user account can manage their email preferences in the member website (Causeway). There is also an unsubscribe option at the bottom of all emails not distributed through Causeway. You can also email us at [admin@team.mipi.org](mailto:admin@team.mipi.org) with a specific request to be removed from MIPI Alliance’s email list. Please understand that if you opt out of receiving email from MIPI Alliance, we may still contact you in connection with your membership, registrations, certifications, or other transactions with us.

#### Personal data about minors and children

MIPI Alliance does not knowingly collect data from or about children under 16 without the permission of parent(s)/guardian(s). If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under 16, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under age 16, please contact us.

#### How will you know if the privacy policy is changed?

MIPI Alliance may update its privacy policy from time to time. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email if you have a MIPI Alliance user account, or by means of a notice on the MIPI Alliance website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

#### Technical and regulatory information

##### Logging practices

MIPI Alliance automatically records the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of visitors. The IP address is a unique number assigned to every computer on the internet. Generally, an IP address changes each time you connect to the internet (it is a "dynamic" address). Note, however, that if you have a broadband connection, depending on your individual circumstance, the IP address that we collect may contain information that could be deemed identifiable. This is because, with some broadband connections, your IP address doesn’t change (it is "static") and could be associated with your personal computer.

As well as recording the IP addresses of users, MIPI Alliance may also keep track of sites that users visited immediately prior to visiting MIPI Alliance’s website and the search terms they used to find it. We keep track of the pages visited on MIPI Alliance’s website, the amount of time spent on those pages and the types of searches done on them. Your searches remain confidential and anonymous. MIPI Alliance uses this information only for statistical purposes to find out which pages users find most useful and to improve the website.

MIPI Alliance also captures and stores information that you transmit. This may include:

  * Browser/device type/version
  * Operating system used
  * Media access control (MAC) address
  * Date and time of the server request
  * Volume of data transferred

##### External links behavior

Some of MIPI Alliance’s websites link to other sites created and maintained by other public- and/or private sector organizations. MIPI Alliance provides these links solely for your information and convenience.

When you transfer to an outside website, you are leaving the MIPI Alliance domain, and MIPI Alliance’s information management policies no longer apply. MIPI Alliance encourages you to read the privacy statement of each external website that you visit before you provide any personal data.

##### Cookies and web beacons

Cookies and web beacons are electronic placeholders that are placed on your device by websites to track your individual movements on that website over time. MIPI Alliance uses both session-based cookies (which last only for the duration of the user’s session) and persistent cookies (which remain on your device and provides information about the session you are in and waits for the next time you use that site again).

These cookies and web beacons provide useful information to MIPI Alliance, enabling us to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user’s access to and use of our sites, allows us to track usage behavior, and to balance the usage of our websites on all MIPI Alliance web servers.

Tracking cookies, third-party cookies, and other technologies such as web beacons may be used to process additional information, enable non-core functionalities on the MIPI Alliance website and enable third-party functions (such as a social media “share” link). We may also include web beacons and other similar technology in promotional email messages to determine whether the messages have been opened.

##### Do Not Track (DNT)

The online advertising industry has self-regulatory initiatives designed to provide consumers a choice in the types of ads they may see online and to conveniently opt-out from online behavioral ads served by some or all of the companies participating in these programs. Our websites do not respond to DNT consumer browser settings.

##### Collaboration with authorities

MIPI Alliance has appointed its Managing Director to serve as its data protection officer to represent regulatory authorities inside the MIPI Alliance organization, and in return represent the MIPI Alliance organization to regulatory authorities.

The MIPI Alliance data protection officer will ensure proper communication with the relevant regulatory authority for privacy. The data protection officer will also lead investigative action, complaint handling and data breach notification. The data protection officer will also monitor regulatory changes and consult the regulatory authority where implementation of a regulatory or technological change leads to doubt.

##### Responses to legal requests

MIPI Alliance reserves the right to share your information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law.

In the event of bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this privacy policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity.

##### Your European Union privacy rights

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation EU 2016/679) (also known as GDPR), if you are an individual protected by the GDPR you may have certain rights as a data subject. To request information about or avail yourself of those rights, please send an email to [admin@team.mipi.org](mailto:admin@team.mipi.org) with "GDPR Request" in the subject line. In the email please describe, with specificity, the GDPR right you are requesting assistance with. Please note additional information may be requested prior to initiation of a request and that MIPI Alliance reserves the right to charge a fee with respect to certain requests. Upon MIPI Alliance’s completion of its review you will be notified if your request has been granted, denied, or exemptions apply.

#### How do I contact you if there is an issue?

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy or about the use of your personal information, please feel free to contact [admin@team.mipi.org](mailto:admin@team.mipi.org).  
MIPI Alliance  
445 Hoes Lane  
Piscataway, NJ 08854 USA
